{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "What is the definition of calibration",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Calibration is the process of configuring an instrument to provide a result for a sample within an acceptable range",
        "b": "Calibration is configuring and verifying a measuring instrument's accuracy to ensure its readings match a known standard",
        "c": "Calibration means comparing with standard device and adjusting it for accuracy within the limit",
        "d": "All"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is traceability?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Traceability is the ability to identify and follow something or someone, or to keep track of information",
        "b": "Traceability in calibration is the ability to link the readings of a measuring instrument to a known reference standard",
        "c": "Traceability means knowing and documenting the reference instrument used for calibration of device under test",
        "d": "All"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "What should be the standard operating region of the sensors used in any idustry?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "20% to 80 %",
        "b": "30 % to 70%",
        "c": "0 % to 100 %",
        "d": "10% to 90 %"
		
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	{
      "question": "On what basis the sensors are selected for specific application in an industry?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Range of the sensor",
        "b": "Accuracy and Linearity in the operating region",
        "c": "Cost of the sensor",
        "d": "All"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	
	{
      "question": "In which stage of the project the design strategy is freezed?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "At the time of proposal",
        "b": "At the time of Errection stage",
        "c": "At the time of Commissioing stage",
        "d": "At the time of detailed engieering"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	
	{
      "question": "As a standard practice how much settling time we should configure for storing  the readings to PLC for this set-up?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Depends on plant lay-out",
        "b": "Depends on settling time of sensor",
        "c": "Greater than the settling time of sensor but minimum equal to settling time of process",
        "d": "The scan time of PLC"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "For calibration of temperature sensor in your opinion which sensor will be the best as 'Standard' sensor?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "RTD",
        "b": "Thermocouple",
        "c": "Thermister",
        "d": "Fiber optic"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "What safety feature needs to be included in this set-up  so as to avoid any accident?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Necessary interlocks",
        "b": "Emergency STOP push button",
        "c": "Redundancy at PLC level",
        "d": "'Fail Safe' operation for all components"
		
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	{
      "question": "Will there be any effect of installation of temperature sensor in thesystem as regards to accuracy of the readings?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Yes",
        "b": "No"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	
	{
      "question": "Will there be any change in calibration set-up as regards to application for which it will be used?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Yes",
        "b": "No"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
  
  
  
  ]
}
